



Dennis Mai

Full Stack Web Developer



dennismai.dev



Champery, Switzerland



+41 76 400 15 44

Freelance and Contract Web Developer, committed to improving business outcomes. I utilize my experience in business, education and programming to distill problems to their essence, collaborate with my team, and provide simple, powerful solutions with technology. I am fluent in M/ PERN stacks and have a keen eye for crafting user-centered experiences and designs.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer & Contractor

Self-Employed -- Champery, Switzerland

08/2018 - Present

- Strategically create and market digital campaigns for businesses and individuals
- Budget, scope, and plan projects with clear deliverables, timelines, & responsibilities
- Continuously communicate and collaborate with stakeholders while developing technical solutions
- + Achievements:
 - Prototyped Quiz app UI (https://www.triviaquizgame.com not maintained) using PHP, Tailwind & Javascript
 - Revised proprietary crawlers for https://www.collegeconsensus.com/ using Puppeteer in Node.js
- Business Analyst Inventory Specialist

DeinDeal AG -- Zurich, Switzerland

06/2014 - 11/2016

- Orchestrate complex operations between multiple departments for major online events and inventory management
- Gather, clean, and process raw data to optimize purchasing & sales decisions for sales potential vs. financial risk
- + Tasked with improving Inventory Turnover from 7 months to industry-appropriate benchmarks. Spear-headed major online sales events, analyzed pricing & product lifecycles, and coordinated with other departments. Drastically reduced Inventory Turnover to 3-5 months within 2 months of implementation and re-defined company category management.

Technical Skills

+ Frameworks & Libraries

React+Redux, Apollo, Styled-Components,
Express, Electron, Tailwind, Bootstrap

Scripting Languages Javascript ES5+, Node, Typescript, Python3 Devops, Testing & Deployment Docker, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Travis, Heroku, Netlify

(+) Markup & Style
HTML5, ejs, CSS3, SCSS,
CSS-in-JS, CSS-in-CSS

Databases PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, mySQL, Redis

Figma, Zeplin, Gimp Inkscape, Adobe XD

Design Tools

Collaboration & Productivity
Git, Github, Bitbucket, Gitlab,
Jira, Salesforce, Google, Microsoft

Languages & Education

Natural Languages

Fluent Written & Verbal: English, French, Spanish Conversational: Swiss-German, German, Vietnamese

Education

Wichita State University — 2007-2012

BBA Economics 3.9 GPA
BA Spanish 3.8 GPA